<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | The Imp]]></title>
  <link href="http://ferdv.github.io/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ferdv.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-18T15:57:30+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ferdv.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ferdinand Vesely]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ferdv.github.io/blog/2015/02/18/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-18T16:19:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ferdv.github.io/blog/2015/02/18/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For some time I have been contemplating the idea of starting my own blog.
Usually, I have sent that idea to
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Null_device">/dev/null</a> fairly quickly,
convincing myself that there are many blogs run by people that have something
more interesting to say than me. Moreover, they probably present it to the
world in a better way than I would be able to. This time I held the thought
long enough to actually decide to give it a go. This post is an introduction as
well as a statement of intent. You might want to skip it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I think two things contributed to my decision to start a personal blog. First,
I&rsquo;ve discovered the
<a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> blogging framework which looked so
interesting that I wanted to find a use for it. The second inspiration came
from the excellent blog of <a href="http://matt.might.net/">Matt Might</a> and his post
<a href="http://matt.might.net/articles/how-to-blog-as-an-academic/">6 blog tips for busy academics</a>
which robbed me of any remaining excuses for not trying. I find Matt&rsquo;s
collection of articles to be one of the most consistently interesting, highly
readable and useful on the Internet. If you are interested in theory as well as
practical aspects of programming languages, then definitely browse his blog and
add his RSS feed to your reader now!</p>

<p>A part of my motivation for having a blog is to improve my writing and to
collect notes on various topics. However, my hope is that I will be able to
occasionally contribute material deemed interesting or useful by at least one
person other than me. If you end up here while looking for a solution to some
problem, or for a clarification on some subject and I manage to help you, then
I will have succeeded.</p>

<p>The subjects I intend to touch in my posts are obviously based on my interests
and should range over topics such as programming, theory and practice of
programming languages, operating systems, Linux, computer science in general,
and music. I might include some general rants about everyday annoyances.</p>

<p>Why &ldquo;The Imp&rdquo;? Well, I like what the <em>Cambridge Advanced Learner&rsquo;s Dictionary</em>
has to say about <em>imp</em>:</p>

<blockquote><ul>
<li>a small evil spirit</li>
<li><p>(often humorous) a child that behaves badly, but in a way that is funny
rather than serious:</p>

<p>&ldquo;Come here, you little imp!&rdquo;</p></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Also, it is an abbreviation of <em>impostor</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
